One retail broker once told me that
retail traders are like grass. Grass
goes up, you have to get all these new
retail traders and at that time they
might blow up. So basically you're
cutting the lawn and then you have to
find new retail traders.
Retail traders look to where there's
volatility and so they'll move a lot of
people are saying that you're they're
seeing retail traders move into gold
because there's more volatility in gold
or they're seeing more volatility in
copper so they're moving into copper. So
they're very finicky. They don't care as
much about what the underlying they care
more about what they're going to get out
of the contract. Whereas I think our
traders because they're institutional
they're doing a lot of hedging as
opposed to just pure speculation.
This fall in retail volume on the crypto
markets over the last year year and a
half and they're sort of guessing could
this be because
ICE announced that January was the
strongest trading month in the company's
history. You get lots more volume when
there's volatility. If you have too much
volatility people will pull back. If
things are falling too fast or moving up
too high people will start to hold their
positions. Are you seeing an energy
constraint or shortage?
that in the crypto winter sort of 2021
institutions started to come in but
pulled back. Whereas now the belief is
really that they're here. They've
already started to put more funds
towards crypto and it's they're not
going to be pulling back. How do you see
risk versus uncertainty? Tariffs, fire.
What about war? As a risk manager I
would stop people doing something
I have Jennifer Ilkiw with me.
She is such an amazing person, the
president of ICE Futures US, probably
one of the most successful people I've
ever talked to. Oh,
oh thanks Bonnie but I don't think so.
But
>> [clears throat and laughter]
>> I really appreciate that. I'm really
happy to be here. You talked about
living in Asia for a bit just earlier.
yeah, I lived in Singapore for 20 years.
So when I was first in university I
really wanted to try to move to Asia in
basic expand my career. My first
university when I went into my MBA there
was a lot of students from China there
and it felt like if I went there China
was opening up everything was going to
change. So I did an exchange program to
Singapore and I just never left. So you
loved it there? it. I loved it. I really
I enjoy I love the heat. So I do like
the heat that helped but I also really
like the people. I had gone to National
University of Singapore for four months
and it just felt right. So I ended up
I'd been married at the time. My husband
came over. He was a teacher and I just
looked for a job and eventually found
something first with the Singapore
government then I went to the NYMEX and
then I joined ICE not long after that.
So I've been with ICE 18 years now and
four of them in Singapore. It was great.
a lot of very interesting stuff. So we
were just talking about different
futures. This is a whole new
world. world. It's not completely
opposite to crypto. So yeah, so the the
part of the exchange that I run of the
exchange I run ICE Futures US originally
started in 1870 with a cotton exchange.
So these are long long term contracts
and they used to change and adjust over
time but our big softs contracts are
coffee, sugar, cocoa, cotton and orange
juice and we price the world's cotton
and coffee and we have grading
facilities in our New York Stock
Exchange where cocoa pods come in and
there's somebody who'll sit there. We
have cocoa graders that come and they
open it up and they check how much mold
how much slate there is in each of the
cocoa. They and determine whether or not
it can be delivered to the exchange and
on the coffee side green coffee beans
come in. They check the color and the
size of the coffee beans. They roast it
in roasters that are backed from the
early 1900s and then they take the
roasted coffee, they grind it and they
cup it and taste it. So it's it's
absolutely and we price the world's
coffee. So it's a really incredible very
physical. It's it's a beautiful thing
cuz crypto doesn't you don't see crypto.
>> Yeah. Right? It's sort of very very much
in your head and in other ways but this
is very very physical and it's a
fantastic thing to see. That is so
different from how I pictured it. I
thought it was just like a platform with
all numbers. You actually see the
products.
>> We actually see the products coming in
and when we work with the cotton guys
I've gone down to like Memphis and see
where they're growing the cotton and how
the ginning works and everything. It's a
it is really interesting cuz it's much
more hands-on. And we do cocoa, coffee.
They're from different parts of the
world.
>> of the world. So a lot of coffee that
comes in is from Brazil and you get a
lot of cocoa from Ivory Coast, from
Ghana,
Venezuela and everything all over the
place. It's a fantastic really
interesting market. How do you
quantify let's say weather effect or the
possibility of different things
happening in that region?
Um so a lot of it so the traders
basically come on and they trade. So
they're the ones that are looking at
where the prices of it's going to go.
For example cocoa prices were very
volatile over the last year and a half
and it was just supply issues. So it's
very much supply and demand. Though
tariffs with and trade also impacted as
well. So with tariffs coming on there
was concern of is cocoa going to be
included in the tariffs coming into the
US? Is coffee going to be included? How
do the different traders manage it? So
they go on and there's full transparency
cuz they can see what people are buying
and selling it at. Um so it gives them
all it's it's the best way for them to
have price discovery. And we have actual
farmers and stuff trading these products
and coming on and they'll look at the
prices and determine what they're going
to sell their coffee or sugar or cocoa
for. It's really it's it's a really fun
part of the
exchange.
>> I would I understand if farmers or let's
say people that works in the food
industry related industry they want to
trade these products. But what about you
know average traders? How do they just
decide one day I'm going to trade orange
juice futures?
Um it's like on the retail side of it.
>> Yeah. Yeah, so we don't have a huge
amount of retail traders. We tend to
have it's predominantly institutional
traders that end up trading on our
market. So you do get the odd retail
that guy that comes in and I think they
look at the volatility. It's almost the
same as in crypto. People look at the
volatility in Bitcoin and they want to
be able to get some edge and that's
where you get the retail traders
sometimes coming in. But mostly it's
probably largely institutional that we
end up serving in these markets.
What type of decisions do you make every
day? So a lot of my stuff is regulatory
at the moment. So we work for example a
lot with the CFTC. That's our main
regulator. So we'll do things from
trying to understand what types of rules
they're putting in place, trying to meet
with the new chairman of the CFTC,
understand what his strategy is.
We do things where we work with
different clients. We'll call up and
they'll be happy or not happy as the
case may be and we try to solve their
problems. We do a lot of business
development as well. So this is where
we're doing sort of our crypto side of
it was clients are actually speaking to
our product side on the asset management
side and they're sort of saying you know
you're doing a bunch of equity
derivatives. Are you guys looking at
crypto?
So then we start looking at different
crypto contracts and what people want to
do. So it's a
it's sometimes there's the days where
you have meeting by meeting and you
don't know what the next meeting is and
you kind of turn on your Zoom and you
kind of flip from talking about cocoa to
talking about equity derivatives or
going into a regulatory conversation.
Yeah.
>> really it's it's fun. It's challenging
and fun and it makes me think every day.
Similar to kind of what you do cuz you
go from
speaker to speaker.
>> Yeah. Doing talking about completely
different things.
>> do amazing things but very different.
Yeah, very different. Um I had Michael
Turpin on. He was talking about Bitcoin
and now we're talking about cocoa and
orange juice and coffee. That's amazing.
Why do we need help me understand
orange juice futures.
Yes.
>> we need that?
So people are trying to figure out what
the price of orange juice and how
they're going to sell the actual raw
concentrate orange juice. It's kind of
like if you also it might be easier to
think about it in the terms of coffee.
If you're going to be a large coffee
producer and you want to go out and sell
your coffee you want to have an idea of
what you're going to sell it at and you
can look on our markets and say this is
where this certain grade of coffee is
going to sell at. And you might have a
better type of coffee. You might have a
higher grade but you know okay this
coffee is selling at this price this
grade which is the one that is on the
exchange and then you might add a basis.
So you're adding a little extra on top
of that or your coffee might be a little
bit worse so you're taking off and
selling it a little bit less. But it
helps you understand where the world
price is going and how you can be able
to sell that price. And also you can
look forward and say I'm selling this
coffee now but look the forward prices
are higher. I might actually store it
and choose to sell it in the future.
But okay, fire in Brazil. How do you
quantify that? That's my question. Well
we so we don't quantify it the traders
quantify it quantify it.
>> you do you have an idea how they do it
cuz I I have no idea. Um I just want to
know roughly. Yeah, so I I'm guessing
what they do is they figure out the
supply is and if there's a lot of supply
they know the prices are going to go
down but if there's fires there's
clearly going to be less supply and
there's going to be problems so prices
are going to go up. So then if you're
going to have less amount of something
it's kind of like the idea of Bitcoin.
The whole idea is that Bitcoin's going
to stop and the price will go up. And
this is the same thing. It just it
changes over time where we kind of know
when there's when Bitcoin is going to
stop being produced whereas with coffee
sometimes you have more and sometimes
you have less, so you have a much more
volatile market.
>> But what I'm trying to understand is,
okay, with Bitcoin, you can see the
numbers on chain, right? You can see
there's a rule. But with things like
weather or fire, how do you even No,
okay, there's fire, but does that mean
we have 10% less supply or does that
mean 50? Okay, well, sometimes,
depending on the market, they'll have
people on the ground Right.
>> what's happening. There's GPS locators
that can look at what's happening with
regards to how many coffee plantations
and how much is actually growing. And in
the cocoa markets, you see that quite a
bit. There will be people that write
reports on how the pods of the of or the
cocoa pods are. Are they good cocoa
pods? Is there enough fertilizer going
in to the ground to be able to create
better
um cocoa pods?
So So yeah, so there are people that
actually go down and look at the bean,
the bean count, and they they check
everything. They sell that information,
traders look at that information, make a
determination. Different traders will
probably have more physical
understanding, either they'll go down
there or their own company will have
different farms down there where they
can look at it, and then they decide
what the price is going to be. That is
fascinating.
>> really
>> sounds like when when we say say trader
in crypto, it's like a single single
trader, but that's a big group.
>> This is what it would be a big group. So
often you're looking at trading groups
that that will have multiple traders
going in. So when we talk to a company
that will have multiple traders trading
the same products, where you're right,
sometimes crypto is just one lone person
trying to figure out what they're what
they're going to do, and they just look
at different things. Like these guys
would look at what's happening in the
weather, are there fires, are there
droughts? And like I'll get reports of
how much um
water or how much rainfall there is in
India, and if that's going to impact
sugar, for example. You have to be very
knowledgeable.
>> well, I don't have to.
>> [laughter]
>> I get it, and I get like a high a high
view, because we look cuz we do this, we
also price the world or US natural gas
and power. So when we had a big winter
storm coming through in the US, we had
to sort of check to see what's happening
in different parts of the US. Are there
brownouts, are there going to be
concerns, what is happening to the
price? So we really had to sort of look
at that as well. Since we're talking
about energy, are you seeing an energy
constraint or shortage because of AI?
So it's interesting. I don't think I'm
seeing cuz I'm a little bit more removed
from the energy space in in some ways,
especially in the oil space. And there's
a lot of people talking about how do
you're going to look at data centers and
how much is is being used. Um I don't
think we're seeing that in the US at the
moment, and I'm hearing everything from
different people's theories, different
people's Some of them is
we expect prices to go down because
there's going to be mo more ways of
developing energy in certain states, so
that the the total price will go down.
They'll have Do you see what I mean?
There's going to be more energy for the
data centers, so overall price should go
down. And then people turn around and
say, actually, all the energy's going to
be used towards data center, it's going
to drive people's prices up. So I think
there's probably a lot of people with
different incentives on how they're
going to develop that story, and nobody
really knows
at the moment. Interesting.
>> Yeah.
But it's funny.
>> Elon Musk is talking about sending solar
panels to Do I know I was reading about
that.
>> I know.
>> Because, you know, he's expecting we
will need a lot more energy. Yep. So he
goes in and it's and if you're closer to
the sun,
you should get more energy.
>> Yep, there is It's more efficient, yeah.
Um February the 3rd, ICE announced that
January was the strongest trading month
in the company's history.
Congratulations. We've we've done very
well. Volume has increased across all of
our markets. Um some of the things when
you look at ICE,
we're over we've been in the the
business for over about two and a half
decades now. When we really focus on
things, we believe that there's it
should be very simple. We should be
looking at infrastructure that is
neutral, that is trusted, and that works
no matter what the market is. So you
know, you have a lot of exchanges where
there's always concerns if the market's
going to go down, especially when things
are volatile. We invest a huge amount
into infrastructure and into
everything related to technology that we
put in for our own technology, so that
we know that we can manage it and make
sure that the exchange stays up. So when
you have events like when COVID and
prices fell or you have the great
financial crisis and you have all these
different liquidity problems, um and the
market moves quickly,
our exchange stays up. So people have to
trust it and know that no matter what
when they get there, they can find out
what the price is, or there's full price
transparency. There's full price
discovery,
um and that their capital is well used
as well. When you look at numbers go up,
that means a lot of people are trading.
Yeah, when you have more and more
volume, we have more and more traders.
Right, what does that mean? Is that the
market is about to turn? Is that It it
depends. So we don't really look at
where the market is going from our side,
we have to be very neutral. We just
provide the platform, so we have no part
of our company that has an incentive to
drive market prices up or down. We just
provide the platform, and that's where
traders make their decisions. So crypto
exchanges see big volume when the price
is shooting up or dropping very
drastically.
>> and so any volatility will cause volumes
to go up and down. Correct, yeah. So
it's the same way in our market. So for
if you're going to start seeing prices
start to go up a lot, and prices in
commodities tend to they go up, but
there's not a sort of a shoot up, it's
still sort of
what do they say? Um the prices go up on
a escalator and down in a lift, right?
So you always see a huge amount of price
movement on the way down and a lot of
vola- volatility and more trading on the
way down. Whereas if prices are solely
prices tend to go up a little bit more
slowly. But yeah, but it's the same
idea.
You get lots more volume when there's
volatility. If you have too much
volatility, people will pull back
because they get a little bit They try
to get a little bit scared. It's
probably the same in the crypto markets.
I would think that if things are fa-
falling too fast or moving up too high,
people will start to hold their
positions as well. And I'm I'm just
wondering, like when people retail
investors or investors in general see
that news that you guys have really high
trading volume, I'm just wondering, what
are they thinking now?
Um
they probably realize how
broad and diverse an offering we have.
So like we have everything from you have
a great interest rate um portfolio all
the way to our energy complex and Brent
is where the world prices or every- the
world prices is oil at ICE. Yeah. And so
they look at Brent, and that's the
world's prices oil. They price all of
their softs, they price all of their gas
and power at ICE. So I think they start
to realize that we become a bigger and
bigger force in the markets with regards
to pricing
various commodities all the way across
all the asset classes.
What are some really strange things that
has futures?
That I would never expect. Well, and so
in not in not in on our markets, I
always thought China has an apple
futures contract that does very well
from what I understand, and that to me
is always a little bit sort of esoteric
where people
>> Only in China? Only in China, yeah.
>> Why?
Do not know. Do not know, but they have
an apple futures contract. I always
thought that was a pretty amazing thing.
But then we have things for battery
metals and lithium all the way through.
Our oil complex has thousands of
different contracts. So well, people
will trade Brent, Dubai. We also have
Singapore fuel oil, and we have gas oil
and jet fuel all the way down to very
It's not really esoteric, but very
specific energy contracts that that
different trading companies will want to
trade.
What are some things you think should
have futures?
That is a good question. Um we have
often have requests for
sort of nuts and seeds sometimes. We get
requests for almonds. Mhm. Um
it's a little bit more Some markets are
difficult to price because they're not
transparent. So you often have to find a
market that has some transparency.
A lot of people Some people have asked
for diamond futures, which has always
been a bit difficult, um also not
transparent. Tea seems like an obvious
one because you could sort of have But
there's no futures contract in tea.
Sometimes I think and like there's rice.
People used to have a lot of rice
contracts in Japan, and that's more or
less disappeared. But I think these
things are Sometimes it sort of comes
and goes, but also I think the way
people trade starts to change, and some
people like a lack of transparency in
some trading.
Right? Because if there's an opaque
market, some people can make more money
off of an opaque market.
>> When you say transparency, are we
talking about, you know, Price
transparency. Yeah.
>> The ability like if you know where
prices are, some people really
A a very commoditized market is very
good cuz you have a lot of price
transparency, and it's easier to
discover the price. Whereas some markets
that are smaller don't have that same
price discovery. It's probably the same
as if you're looking at some altcoins,
where's the transparency in those prices
with altcoins? Well, there are a few
whales that owns a lot, and the founders
and the team probably owns a lot. Is
that what you're saying? Well, I guess
when you look at I sort of sometimes
think of altcoins, there's less people
in there to necessarily always
understand exactly how the founders make
decisions. And they probably have a lot
of
I don't know as much about the market,
but I'm guessing that there's a little
bit of opaqueness because they want to
sort of protect some things as well. If
there's a little bit of opaqueness,
you're not sure how to price something,
then there might be less people getting
into that market.
Do you have people coming up to you and
say, "Hey, I think we should have this
futures," and do you look into it?
>> Always, yeah. We always look and try to
decide if we're going to do that, and
that's how it started with the crypto
contracts. So people said, "We need to
have these crypto contracts," and that's
why we decided to do it. But we also
sometimes people suggest, and there's
just no market for it, or we can't find
a price. So we have with our softs
contracts, we do the physical delivery
like I explained with the cocoa and
coffee, but a lot of our energy
contracts, they're cash settled. And so
a PRA is same same ideas coin desk. So
they're almost a index provider and then
you have MSCI and then in the energy
markets you have Platts or fast markets.
So PRA will provide they will get that
price discovery and they'll be a number
you can settle off of but sometimes it's
impossible to find the number and
because people will sit down and
basically in some commodities they'll
sit at a coffee table and decide what
the price is going to be. There's no way
of getting all of those numbers putting
it together and figuring out a
settlement price. But firms will look
into it. We're seeing more into rare
earths now.
So what usually happens is these price
reporting agencies find new avenues of
where people want to find out numbers
and they go and do what they get they
start calling around the market or they
get what they call herds. So they hear
different numbers. They put these
numbers together and then try to figure
out where the price should be. And when
that gets a little bit more consistent
and people start to trust it then we can
launch a futures contract off of that.
You talked about delivery. So you can
actually see these products. What about
you know, let's say oil and natural gas?
Um yes, so there's no physical delivery
in those contracts. So those contracts
are cash settled contracts. So we don't
see the oil. I mean CME which is another
exchange they have physical delivery in
WTI. So they will actually have the
physical delivery on that but we don't
have that. And so usually if you've got
smaller players that don't want to go
into physical delivery our clearing
members. So how our world works in the
margin senses you have the exchange and
you have a client and they have a
clearing member that sits in between. So
if it's a client that might not be
someone who should take delivery into
cocoa the clearing member will basically
close off their position if they
forgotten to beforehand cuz I remember
years ago when I had worked in
in the markets with NYMEX we would get
clients calling up and saying I forgot
to close out my position. I'm supposed
to get WTI delivered but I'm not a
refinery. What do we do? And then you
have to get them to somebody has to go
and take the opposite side of that
position to close it out. Who is that
somebody? It used to be somebody on the
floor in the past or another oil trader
will go in and and take the opposite
position for someone so then you're
closing off that that trade. What if
nobody wants to take it?
Is it is it is that possible?
>> there's always a price somebody on the
other side will take. Yeah. Yeah. So if
you're long if you are going to get it
and I know that I can take the other
side of it I would just charge you a lot
more money to close out of that
position.
Cuz it's you'll take the you'll you'll
spend the money cuz it is probably
better than having to deal with oil
barrels showing up at your
>> Yeah, so
forgetting to close it's devastating.
Yeah, it just yeah it just ends up
costing you more money. We have
perpetual contracts in crypto. It's a
unique thing we have in crypto.
Exchanges are doing this thing and
they're controlling well not controlling
they're
maintaining the price with funding rate
and that is very different
>> than how we do cuz we have monthly
contracts that end and that's really how
the CFTC regulates things at the moment.
Currently perpetuals in the same sense
you see in crypto is not allowed in well
it's it's allowed but it's considered a
swap it's not considered a futures
contract so it has different regulatory
requirements and you'd end up having
larger margin. So some players are
coming in and they're offering
perpetuals but in a slightly different
way. There is still a final settlement
date.
Oh that's because
>> in because of the way that the US
regulations work. At the moment you
can't have a contract that never ends.
Oh interesting. Okay. Well in the rest
of the world we can
>> You can't you can't Yeah in the
perpetuals in in your space you guys
have contracts that never end.
But my question is why can't this system
be in place
with other products? Like for for
example the cash settlement
uh
category if there's no delivery
technically Yeah, so I guess yeah in
theory it probably could potentially
make more sense in like equity markets
like if you were doing equity derivative
contracts and you could have sort of
that funding rate because the underlying
cash equities will change quite a bit. I
think when it comes to the agricultural
markets it's a little bit more difficult
because of that need to come to a
physical delivery that so that that
part's a little bit different.
Um
but I do see that there could be value
though there hasn't nobody's asked for
it in the equity derivative space.
So I think we're still getting to the
point where the institutional and the
crypto markets are coming together. So
crypto traders are often just crypto
traders and very much in the perpetual
space where the institutional are still
institutional. So we're starting to see
that convergence and you'll see that
with some players where exchanges are
now starting to look at how can they
offer a near perp. So you have a perp
that still has the funding rate but it
usually settles only it settles twice a
day.
That makes sense. You know how you have
often a perp will settle every 8 hours.
So these will settle usually and we
looked at doing it you can settle at
1:00 in the afternoon that's sort of in
the US standard time where we always
take intraday margin calls and then you
would settle at T+1 the following day.
And that is just the way cuz futures
markets really only collect margins
twice a day. So they collect margins at
1:00 p.m. So if there's a a margin call
that needs to be made cuz there's been a
big move in the markets we will collect
margin early just to protect the
clearinghouse and then we collect margin
the following day. So we have a
settlement and then we collect margin
T+1. So what are the things that you
think could happen with this perpetual
contract? Yeah, so I think if there's
perpetuals in more in our more
traditional markets we'll have to get
demand probably from the equity
derivatives guys. That's where I could
sort of see it happening. But at this
point it also seems to be a lot of
retail want to focus on the perpetual
contracts and because we're
predominantly institutional
that we're I think that's why we get a
little bit less demand for anything like
that whereas I would suspect other
exchanges that have a much bigger retail
base would probably be getting people
who are trading on crypto do that. And
the actually the interesting thing we
were talking about in some of the panels
and with people here is the sort of this
fall in retail volume on the crypto
markets over the last year year and a
half. And they're sort of guessing could
this be because you've got more event
markets coming in. Are there other
places where retail traders can go and
trade which you didn't even have a year
ago. And with people saying you know if
you're looking at event markets how are
we seeing those different movements in
retail preferences. Would you like to
elaborate on that? One retail broker
once told me that retail traders are
like grass. Right? So the retail the
grass goes up and you have to get all
these new retails retail traders and at
that time they might blow up so
basically you're cutting the lawn and
then you have to find new retail
traders. Yeah.
>> Right?
And somebody else likened it to a box of
Kleenex or tissue. So you pull out one
and there is always another one there
and you have to keep getting more retail
traders. And so they and they're also
very
they're
retail traders look to where there's
volatility and so they'll move a lot of
people are saying that you're they're
seeing retail traders move into gold
because there's more volatility in gold
or they're seeing more volatility in
copper so they're moving into copper. We
had a lot of retail issue companies
asking about doing retail trading in
cocoa cuz there was a lot of volatility.
So they're very finicky they don't care
as much about what the underlying they
care more about
the the what they're going to get out of
the contract. Whereas I think our
traders because they're institutional
they're doing a lot of hedging as
opposed to just pure speculation. So for
them it's much more we are they're
always going to trade oil cuz they need
to trade oil and they got to hedge their
they have risk management needs or cocoa
or coffee or sugar. And I think with the
retail markets now
you've got more
products for them to trade. So there was
crypto and the perps in crypto. Now
there's event markets. And so it's like
the pie is still here with all the
retail traders but the amount of things
that they can do the pie retail traders
hasn't grown but the amount of things
they can do has grown significantly. And
just ways I think the binary option
seems to be very easy way for
like you can be a retail trader you can
say the price goes up or what's going to
happen to you know is Trump going to be
elected yes or no. It's a very yes or no
answer that is a very easy way for
traders to come in and we're hearing a
lot of younger people just sort of
anecdotally are coming in and starting
to trade those markets.
What is your view on different
cryptocurrencies? I understand that
institutions are more comfortable with
Bitcoin. What about the smaller cap
tokens? Yeah, so what we're starting to
hear through more like family offices
and some asset managers we're talking to
is clients are coming in and said listen
I've done Bitcoin. Great I've got that
and now I'm hearing about ETH and I'm
hearing about Solana I'm hearing about
Ripple. I want to get access to that but
the asset managers
don't have the depth of knowledge in the
other products. So rather than going and
asking this is why we've created these
sort of this is why CoinDesk has created
indices and they're working with ETF
providers and we're creating the
futures. So anybody can basically say
yes well you don't really have to
worry about doing all these individuals
we can give you an index. Just like if
you think of it nobody with our MSCI
emerging markets nobody knows every
single equity contract that is listed
under MSCI emerging markets. But they go
and they're like I want to get access to
emerging markets so I'm going to go to
an index provider I trust I'm going to
trade the futures or the ETF based on
that. And that's basically where
CoinDesk is thinking this with their
CoinDesk 20 and that's we've got a lot
of the same views with them on that.
People want to have something that they
can use as a benchmark.
They really have to trust whoever that's
providing that information.
>> Yes. Yeah. And cuz CoinDesk they one of
the reasons we're work work with
CoinDesk is because people trust them.
They're IOSCO compliant. They've got
regulation out of Europe. They're
regulated in all these different
jurisdictions. They look at the data and
they're very conscious about making sure
that's right data that comes in and then
the right data comes in and they don't
manipulate it to try to change anything.
Your panel is titled the next chapter in
digital asset futures. Yeah, we had that
yesterday. It was really good. Yeah, you
were in a red dress. Uh yes, I was in a
I figured the light Yeah, the the
brighter the colors, the more people can
see you.
It was beautiful. Thank you.
>> What was the main message? I was doing a
live stream, so I couldn't I I couldn't
listen to him.
>> so our main message when we had our
announcement was all the futures
contracts that we are listing, so that
was So, there are two things I did
yesterday. One was the announcement,
which was the futures contracts we're
doing in line with CoinDesk, and really
the relationship the strong relationship
that ICE and CoinDesk have. And then we
were on a second panel, which was
derivatives, and that was myself, we had
FalconX, Galaxy was on that, Ark Invest
was on that, and then CoinDesk was a
moderator. And it was really talking
about where are we seeing crypto
derivatives in both the institutional
and the more crypto worlds going. And
that a lot of it discussion was really
that convergence between, and a lot of
it is uh
US administration and their changes in
focusing on getting more clarity in the
market.
>> your one main takeaway from that panel
discussion? Institutions are coming in
to trade these markets. It is not going
to be an overnight
you know, in the next few weeks we're
going to have tons of institutions
coming in, but over the next 5 to 10
years, this is a place where
institutions are here. I think Jason on
the
on our panel yesterday said that in the
crypto winter instead of 2021,
institutions started to come in but
pulled back. Whereas now the belief is
really that they're here. They've
already started to put more funds
towards crypto, and it's they're not
going to be pulling back, and part of it
is regulatory change. There's not that
fear anymore of potentially doing
something wrong. And that risk of
potentially doing something wrong,
there's a lot more clarity there. So, we
think institutionals will stay as
opposed to pull back.
You've um lived in Asia and obviously
the US.
Have you seen the market
you know, differ because of culture,
because of different
It feels to me that Asia is still
looking a lot more at the traditional
crypto exchanges, whereas I'm feeling in
the US and Europe, they're looking more
toward regulated venues. And I think a
lot of it is the US has been very clear
that we want to take all that
unregulated markets that people are
trading on and make it regulated and
bring that volume internally back into
the US.
So, that's probably what I'm seeing the
most at the moment. People here don't
talk about trying to
trade trade and pay margin. They're
still happy in sort of the the more
traditional space. Mhm. How do you see
risk versus uncertainty?
If there's a risk out there,
you have banks that will say there's too
much risk in crypto, there's too much
unregulated like regulatory risk in it,
we don't understand it. There's There is
no
clarity, so we're not even going to go
in there. When there's uncertainty in
the market, it's prices could go up or
prices could go down. I have an
opportunity to make some money.
So, as a as a risk manager, I would stop
people doing something when there's
when it's risky, but if there's
uncertainty and there's potential to
make money, I would let them do it.
Tariffs.
Okay, so tariffs will provide trading
opportunities for people. Okay. So,
that's uncertainty and there's trading
opportunities to come from there and
potential to make money. What about
fire?
Fire in the sense So, that would give
you a potential trading opportunity
because you don't know how big the fire
is going to be, and you could expect the
prices in co- or in coffee to
potentially go up because the fire is
really big, but they could manage to
keep the fire at bay, and then the
prices will not go as high.
Change of administration. Depends on
where they stand, and it's not clear if
you move from a Republican to a Democrat
um
where they stand at the moment. Right.
>> With regards to crypto, and I think also
with the regulation, once CFTC and SEC
puts the regulation in, we're going to
have quite strong regulation. It's going
to be hard to pull that back. So, I
think even if you have a change
administration 2 years, it feels like
Atkins and the CLike are really trying
to say we want to have this in well
before that happens.
What about war?
War.
Um I think it depending on the trader
you're talking to, they could see
opportunity to make money off of that,
but then you're going to look at
different banks, they're going to be
depending on what a bank is going to do.
Some people might not do things because
there's a risk of being involved.
So, then they'll pull back on what
they're doing.
I think it probably depends what you're
looking at doing. If you're sitting
there and just trading the product
versus if you are a financial
institution that also has or owns oil
tankers. Mhm. Do you see what I mean?
Then they're going to look at it very
differently. So, probably even different
parts of a financial institutional will
look at it differently. So, I think
there's a lot of things that are
happening in these markets
in markets in general and across
different products. So, one of their
examples was self-driving cars, which I
thought this part was fascinating,
nothing to do with our market.
But as you have more self-driving cars,
you decrease the number of accidents
you're having. And most of the accidents
that go end up in the ER are due to car
accidents. So, then you've got less
You've got two things. One, you have
less accidents and less less full ERs,
and then insurance companies have to
decide how they're going to charge you
for insurance for your car because if
you've got a very tiny risk of having a
car accident, do you need to pay as much
insurance anymore? And also more people
live cuz a lot of people die in car
accidents. So, all these different
things and how do you
That could and you might buy less cars
cuz you might cuz less people have
accidents, you're buying less cars. So,
then how does that impact how much steel
people are buying
to make cars?
And is that going to impact Ford and all
these other car companies cuz now they
don't have to make as many cars. It's
fascinating to see to try to figure out
these permutations and what potential
opportunities there are there. Do you Do
you just experience life and then see
different events and be like, oh, this
product is going to go down? It's really
and it's Well, it's it's interesting.
You start looking at all these these
different permutations of what can
actually happen. So, I think a lot of
people are trying to see more
disruptions in the market and how that's
going to impact what they do.
It's so crazy.
>> is going to have crazy disruptions,
right? Everybody talks about that. I
would love to
hear your story and how you get into
this fascinating world.
So, for me, when I moved to Singapore,
my first job ended up being in the
Singapore government with the MAS. And
while I was there, I had met some people
who had come from the New York
Mercantile Exchange, the NYMEX.
SGX, which is the exchange in Singapore,
they were looking at
um
moving into clearing of commodities.
>> Yeah. So, MAS, I was on the development
side, so we were working with SGX to
help them, and then I met people at the
NYMEX. And when I met the people at the
NYMEX, it was this gentleman Tom
McMahon, who actually I just saw a
couple days ago, he's still my mentor.
And he had brought me in to work at the
NYMEX, and he was one guy who was
sitting in Tokyo, and he hired me to
open our Singapore office at the NYMEX,
and there were two of us in Asia. I
basically went out and I got a office
space, like a like what would be
considered sort of a WeWork office space
type thing. I went I bought a computer,
I figured out how to set it up, didn't
know anything about the oil market, so I
went out and started meeting all the oil
traders and the oil brokers, asking them
questions, how do they do, and then
started learning about the oil market
that way.
I spent about 2 and 1/2 years with them.
Um and then I started meeting some
people from ICE. They had offered me a
job opportunity. Uh NYMEX was then being
sold to the CME, so there's a little bit
disruption in at the NYMEX, and there
wasn't clarity. This is where
where's your risk? You have You have
uncertainty, so what do you do? So, I
went to a place that felt a little bit
more certain. So, I ended up joining
ICE, and that was 2007, August of 2007,
and I it started We were tiny, 300
people at the time the company, and it
really felt like a family. Mhm. Like it
was it just felt like a place that
worked for me, and we are now, I think
12 or 13,000 people, so we've grown a
huge amount. And but it still feels like
a family to me. Yeah. They're wonderful,
and it's just and it's grown from there.
And part of it is I think when you love
something, like I love my job. I love
what I do. I love the people I work
with. We are not this sort of company
that doesn't work together as a team. We
are a company that works 100% as a team,
and it feels like we're always trying to
do best for everybody else and trying to
encourage
Like I know my boss encourages me, I try
to encourage anyone who's either my peer
or who's working for me to try to
continue to do better, and just giving
people opportunities.
Um our CEO's always said
it's important to take risks. You might
fail, but you learn from those failures,
and then you take all that knowledge,
and then you keep going.
So, and Jeff really does that. He's a
fantastic person.
Um he's a great
>> mentors? Yeah, I did have a few mentors
along the way. One was this gentleman
Tom McMahon from the NYMEX, and then
actually my father, he was in the
finance business, he
introduced me to someone. It was his
boss at the time, and I remember
I'd always call him if I wasn't sure
what I was going to do with my career. I
love that.
>> Yeah, and it was and I call him and I
talk to him, and I remember at one point
I was looking at working at two banks
and the NYMEX, and I said, "I don't know
what to do." And he said, "You have to
choose a job that is important to you,
not that is going to make your father
proud, not that is going to make your
MBA MBA cohort proud, it's going to make
you happy and excited, and money and
that feeling of success will come." And
I chose NYMEX because at the time it
really felt like it was it was almost an
entrepreneurial job. It was me setting
everything up in Singapore and doing it
all by myself.
And it just yeah, and if I hadn't done
that, I never would have ended up at ICE
and I never would have had what I had
now. And even I remember and I was
telling someone the other day when I
looked I always like people run
exchanges. I would love to do that one
day. And then all of a sudden I got
offered the job to sort of run the
exchange and it's just been it's it's
fantastic.
>> it that fascinates you?
So you every day something is different
and every like I know I love the
regulatory stuff more than I expected
and the personalities and trying to
understand the motivations behind
everything. For me coming into this job,
I'm Canadian so I didn't know that much
about the US
um
regulatory space and so it was a huge
amount of learning. The first year year
and a half in this role was a huge
amount of learning. But it's also the
people. Like
my COO who works for me is fantastic.
The product heads who work are all
fantastic and we just we talk about
everything's new and exciting. And the
people like the the clients and everyone
are smart and intelligent and I get to
meet people like you and have great
conversations. But it it's sort of that
it's it makes you happy and excited.
Like I go home and I tell my kids I love
my job. And you sort of get those days
where you go home and you're just so
energized. Mhm. So I feel always more
energized from my job than exhausted
from my job.
Before um I started doing interview
yesterday. So I was prepping all night
so I didn't really sleep. I was dead
inside. But after a full day of talking
to people, I was like oh my god.
>> Yeah. Yeah.
Yeah. And that's what
>> like three Red Bulls in but I understand
what you're saying. Yeah, cuz I was even
seeing as I was walking by just earlier
just to make sure I knew where I was
going.
And I was seeing you I'm like that's
probably her second day. She must be
really
>> [laughter]
>> tired
on this. But you do but you get
energized cuz you learn things from
everyone. It's the same thing. We learn
I learn every day. What happens when
futures market stop working for a week?
What happens to the world? Well
I think for a lot of traders, they don't
know how to price anything. And then I
think the prices for everything for
coffee, sugar, cocoa, oil markets, all
of that like even during COVID, none of
that stopped. Right.
>> Like the markets did not stop. Like
people either went in or they traded
from home or they shrank hours down to
maybe three or four hours so you made
sure that you were pricing. Because if
people don't know how they're going to
figure out what the price of cocoa's
going to be. If you're a cocoa company
or you're a chocolate company and you
don't know what the price how are you
going to decide what the price of your
chocolate bar is going to be what you're
selling. If you are a company that buys
and sells oil or uses oil as a tanker or
you're an airplane like you're a you run
aviation
>> Yeah aviation and you're running all
these planes and you don't know what the
price of fuel's going to be. How do you
determine what you're going to charge
anybody for this like you everybody
there's so many parts of these markets
that are so intertwined in how you are
going to price
what's going to happen going forward.
How you're pricing airline tickets, how
you're pricing chocolate bars or your
next cup of coffee. It gets very
intricate so I think having a week off,
people would very much struggle and you
would not be able to know how to manage
their risk.
Do you think retail investors, everyday
people will know that's happening? I
think it takes a while to work through
the markets. It's like when we saw that
we knew that there were were issues in
the cocoa markets because of supply
issues, that took a while to feed in and
we sort of sort of knew in sort of six
months chocolate bars are going to get
smaller and you could see there was sort
of shrinkage in the chocolate bars.
They're going to add more nuts for
example in a Mars bar if you start
adding more nuts and caramel, there's
less chocolate. So it takes time and
just like it's going to take time to
move back where people are going to
start adding more chocolate in and
taking that stuff out and out and adding
different products in. So it doesn't
happen immediately.
I'm not sure if the gas at the gas pump
it does. It feels like in the US things
the gas pump seems to change quite
quickly.
Um but I think it would take a while for
the retail markets. To even understand.
>> Yeah. You're obviously very successful.
Uh what are some of the
you know, personal habits that
contributes to the success?
I am very organized about what I do. So
I
every morning I get up at quarter to
five. I exercise every morning for an
hour because for me I need to be able to
have that. I ended up building a gym in
my house to make it easier to be able to
do that.
And then I have two young daughters who
are 12 and 15. I have a very organized
routine of what the morning looks like.
It does feel like chaos sometimes when
we're trying to get out the door and get
them to to school. I'm almost on the
same train every day to be able to get
to the office. And for me I think I need
to have those sort of routines to make
sure that I
can
once you have the routines then there's
less things to think about. I don't have
to think about all those things so then
I can focus on work when I'm at work.
And then when I get home I sleep. I do
sleep early. I'm usually in bed at like
9:15.
Wow. Yeah. So I'm I'm my oldest daughter
probably goes to bed at 11:00 11:30 and
she laughs at me. But I'm in I'm in bed
quite early. Is this trained or is this
does it come natural to you? I am a
morning person so I think that that's
always helped with me. But I
I need to with the exercise I always
need I know I needed to exercise. And so
when I was in Asia it was different. We
used to exercise at lunch hour because
the work world was different where we
worked until 10:00 at night whereas now
I'm only working till 5:00 p.m.
Getting up and making myself get up at
quarter to five is a lot of not thinking
about it. I have my exercise clothes
that are sitting there waiting. I know
exactly what I'm doing. I get on I have
use Peloton so I get on my Peloton app
the night before. I decide what classes
I'm going to take so I don't even have
to think about it in the morning. I wake
up. I roll out and I'm not even probably
really awake until I get down to my gym.
So there aren't days
when you're like I just don't feel like
doing anything.
>> The odd time I've done that and then I
kind of lie in bed and think well that
was a waste of an hour.
Wow. [laughter]
Wow. So then I just lie there and I'm
like that was just dumb. That was just
dumb. So then I I just don't do it. Is
that like a common thing
about sex really successful people or
high performing people?
>> know. That's what works for me. That's
what that's what I need to be able to
do.
>> Do you need people around you to be the
same?
No. No. They can be Like they can do
whatever they want. I don't I'm I'm not
fussed about what they do.
>> you?
No.
No, I might I don't No, it doesn't. And
my kids are certainly not like that.
Yeah. So I can't make them do that. My
oldest daughter she does it she plays
rugby. My youngest plays basketball and
I like them to take to play team sports
and I have I encourage them to do that.
So that they know what it's like to be
in a team and and grow those I there's a
lot of dynamics and things you learn
from being in a team. Um but I think
they need to do things. They take the
garbage out and they have to empty the
dishwasher. My oldest often cooks for us
at night. Um she can cook on her own and
she likes that. So How would your
daughters describe you?
>> 12 and 15. How would they describe me?
Well they watch me on the CoinDesk live
and they're really proud of me and
they're so yeah which is really nice. Um
my youngest daughter, she had a friend
who in class she's 12 years old.
He was talking about all it was all
the fathers that are working and she was
very upset and she was like my mother
has a big job. It's not just fathers
that do well.
>> it. So yeah. She's they it's it's been
lovely to be able to get to show them
that. There are trade-offs because when
I'm working it means I'm not with them.
So it's not like you can do everything.
Yeah. And you know you can't do
everything. But it's trade-offs that
that do work and I'm proud to that they
know that I can support them and take
care of them. And they're proud of you.
Yeah. It's lovely. They're they're it's
really it's really nice. They get to see
that. And hopefully that they sort of
look at the all the different things
that they can achieve. They don't have
to do the same thing that I do. But for
them to be able to see what they can
achieve in the future is important to
me.
They should be really proud because
I'm super inspired. I appreciate your
time. Thank you for being here.
>> so much fun. This has been a great
conversation. I really enjoyed it. Thank
>> Bye-bye.